<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xml:lang="en-US" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/" xmlns:s="http://jadedpixel.com/-/spec/shopify">
  <id>https://www.clementcoffee.com/blogs/news.atom</id>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.clementcoffee.com/blogs/news"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.clementcoffee.com/blogs/news.atom"/>
  <title>Clement Coffee - News</title>
  <updated>2015-08-14T11:13:00+10:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Clement Coffee</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.clementcoffee.com/blogs/news/41073476-mutheka-peaberry</id>
    <published>2015-08-14T11:13:00+10:00</published>
    <updated>2015-08-14T11:14:07+10:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.clementcoffee.com/blogs/news/41073476-mutheka-peaberry"/>
    <title>Mutheka Peaberry</title>
    <author>
      <name>Tayt Bale</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<div style="text-align: center;"><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0403/3485/files/Mutheka_Peaberry_large.jpg?15609950318395636092"></div>
<div style="text-align: center;"></div>
<p class="p1"><b>Mutheka Peaberry</b></p>
<p class="p1">We are very excited to have the delicious Kenya Mutheka at Clement Coffee! </p>
<p class="p1">The Mutheka Farmers Cooperative Society (FCS) consists of more than 5600 active farmer members, approximately 900 of which use the Kigwandi factory. The factory, which is part of the Mutheka FCS, uses hydro electric power from the Kagumo River to run its operations. Smallholder farmers delivering cherry to the Kigwandi factory have an average of 207 coffee trees each and generally farm food crops alongside their small coffee plots.</p>
<p class="p2"> </p>
<p class="p1">Cherries collected from the farmers in the region are bulked together and washed, fermented and laid out on raised beds to dry. The Cooperative puts a lot of focus on quality and are known for their meticulous sorting through the whole process. Although their equipment is old and in need of upgrade, they won a local competition for quality in 20003 and continue to produce exceptional coffee.</p>
<p class="p2"> </p>
<p class="p1">Peaberry beans are a relatively rare occurrence and can occur on any coffee variety. In most instances, a coffee cherry will contain two coffee beans, however when one of the ovules of the cherry fails to develop, the remaining bean with no second bean to provide pressure, will form into a rounded shape with no flat side. They are often separated from the rest of the harvest and sold separately, in most cases commanding a higher price.</p>
<div style="text-align: left;"></div>
<div style="text-align: left;"></div>
<div style="text-align: left;"></div>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.clementcoffee.com/blogs/news/18040368-mornings-at-clement</id>
    <published>2015-04-16T14:10:40+10:00</published>
    <updated>2015-04-16T14:10:40+10:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.clementcoffee.com/blogs/news/18040368-mornings-at-clement"/>
    <title>Mornings at Clement</title>
    <author>
      <name>Tayt Bale</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>Here is a sneak peak of what we do every morning at Clement.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/125092803" width="500" height="281" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.clementcoffee.com/blogs/news/14498981-melbourne-kenyan-safari</id>
    <published>2014-06-16T09:20:00+10:00</published>
    <updated>2014-06-16T09:20:32+10:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.clementcoffee.com/blogs/news/14498981-melbourne-kenyan-safari"/>
    <title>MELBOURNE KENYAN SAFARI</title>
    <author>
      <name>Jared Lawler</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>Kenyan coffees are consistently among the best in the world! They're well known for intensely bright acidity, sugary sweetness and superior cleanliness. </p>
<p><span>In January, Salvatore and Matt Perger went to Kenya to find some delicious coffees for us. </span><span>We are so excited to be serving these coffees at all of our stores in the St Ali Family.  </span></p>
<p>To celebrate the arrival of the Kenyan coffees into the St Ali Family stores we have developed a Kenyan Safari treasure map, where you can make your way from store-to-store tasting all the delicious coffees that Kenya has to offer. Get your map signed off at each location. When you have tasted all your coffees (and completed your map!) you win a prize.</p>
<p>Collect your map from any stores in the St Ali Family:</p>
<ul>
<li><span>St Ali, 12-18 Yarra Place, South Melbourne</span></li>
<li><span>North, 815 Nicholson Street, Carlton North</span></li>
<li><span>Clement Coffee Roasters, Stall 89 / 116 Cecil Street, South Melbourne</span></li>
<li><span>Clement - A Bloc, 116 Commercial Road, Prahran</span></li>
<li><span>Sensory Lab, 297 Little Collins Street, Melbourne</span></li>
<li><span>Tom Thumb Espresso, 53 Flinders Lane, Melbourne</span></li>
<li><span>Plantation, Shop 253, Level 2, Melbourne Central, 300 LaTrobe Street, Melbourne</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0403/3485/files/Kenyan-Safari-Patch_Colour_large.jpg?886" /></span></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.clementcoffee.com/blogs/news/13431661-velo-pour-femme</id>
    <published>2014-04-07T10:57:09+10:00</published>
    <updated>2014-04-07T11:14:49+10:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.clementcoffee.com/blogs/news/13431661-velo-pour-femme"/>
    <title>Velo Pour Femme</title>
    <author>
      <name>Jared Lawler</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<div style="text-align: center;"></div>
<div style="text-align: center;">Looking forward to the all female alley cat. Get your crew together and come join us and <a href="http://www.ponybikes.com/female-alley-cat/" target="_blank" title="more info">Pony bikes</a> on 18th of April.</div>
<div style="text-align: center;"></div>
<div style="text-align: center;"><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0403/3485/files/VELO_POUR_FEMME_3d_grande.jpg?312" /></div>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.clementcoffee.com/blogs/news/13082565-finca-genesis-costa-rica</id>
    <published>2014-03-24T14:43:31+11:00</published>
    <updated>2014-03-24T14:44:20+11:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.clementcoffee.com/blogs/news/13082565-finca-genesis-costa-rica"/>
    <title>Finca Genesis - Costa Rica</title>
    <author>
      <name>Jared Lawler</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>In 2008 this coffee was part of the Cup of Excellence winning lot, back then it was blended with other coffees from the Mendez’ farm.  </p>
<p>Oscar and Olga Mendez named this farm Genesis to mean the beginning, as now they own their own micro mill and are processing their own lots so their coffees can be sold independently and not blended.  </p>
<p>Sourced directly by the crew at Sensory Lab this is a standout espresso and absolutely stunning filter.</p>
<p>Enjoy</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img src="http://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0403/3485/files/Screen_Shot_2014-03-24_at_2.43.20_pm.png?224" /></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.clementcoffee.com/blogs/news/13082557-el-bosque-guatemala</id>
    <published>2014-03-24T14:42:06+11:00</published>
    <updated>2014-03-24T14:43:14+11:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.clementcoffee.com/blogs/news/13082557-el-bosque-guatemala"/>
    <title>El Bosque - Guatemala</title>
    <author>
      <name>Jared Lawler</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>Being well into Central American season it’s time to get to know some of our coffees.</p>
<p>First up is a delicious Guatemalan from a farm titled El Bosque. The  progressive farmers own their own wet mill which gives Julio, José, Francisco and Mario Flores complete control over the drying process.</p>
<p>This is a classic Guatemalan full of sweet stonefruits reminiscent of white peach. Chocolate and caramel notes balance out the coffee and a creamy mouthfeel is lingering.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img src="http://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0403/3485/files/Screen_Shot_2014-03-24_at_2.41.50_pm.png?222" /><img src="http://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0403/3485/files/Screen_Shot_2014-03-24_at_2.41.43_pm.png?223" /></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.clementcoffee.com/blogs/news/13082541-sitio-canaa</id>
    <published>2014-03-24T14:39:05+11:00</published>
    <updated>2014-03-24T14:41:37+11:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.clementcoffee.com/blogs/news/13082541-sitio-canaa"/>
    <title>Sitio Canaa</title>
    <author>
      <name>Jared Lawler</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<div style="text-align: center;"><em><em><img src="http://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0403/3485/files/Screen_Shot_2014-03-24_at_2.38.42_pm.png?221" />﻿</em></em></div>
<p>Introducing one of our newest coffees, Sitio Canaa!</p>
<p>Produced by farmers Joao Hamilton and Ivan Dos Santos who inherited the farm from their fathers, this micro-lot from the region of Mococa in Brazil is of the Red Catuai variety, naturally processed and grown at an altitude of 1200-1340 meters above sea level. The farm itself is 10 hectares, and produces a number of different coffee varieties, consisting of Catuai, Mundo Novo, Sumatra and Bourbon. As far as environmental attributes go, Sitio Canaa has some of the best natural resources going around, with plenty of light, a high altitude, a rainforest climate, wild-life aplenty and mineral-rich volcanic soil.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img src="http://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0403/3485/files/Screen_Shot_2014-03-24_at_2.39.14_pm.png?220" /></p>
<p>Originally, the focus of this farm was to produce as much quantity as possible with the use of various agro-toxic chemical. But in 2006 the Fazenda Ambiental Fortaleza (abbreviated, the FAF is a farm located in the mountain Mogiana region of Brazil which has been operating as a coffee plantation since 1850, but more importantly also act as a kind of ‘umbrella’ for a group of regional farmers) decided to take on board Joao and Ivan to become involved in a new and more sustainable approach to producing coffee. Their focus shifted to achieving the highest quality coffee whilst simultaneously respecting nature and therefor ensuring the security of the future of the farm for their family. They reforested the area around natural springs in order to maintain and protect them, began recycling all trash, and refraining from using any toxic fertilizers and herbicides. This shift in focus also resulted in the production of a higher quality of coffee and an overall more balanced and natural growth for the area and the coffee plants. The harvesting methods also changed, as they decided to begin selecting the ripest cherries, experimenting with semi-washed pulping techniques and working more carefully on the drying patios. Together, Joao, Ivan and Marcos Croce, the farm co- owner from FAF strive to achieve further development of higher quality coffees.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img src="http://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0403/3485/files/Screen_Shot_2014-03-24_at_2.39.21_pm.png?219" /></p>
<p> </p>
<p>This is Joao</p>
<p>This coffee has had a seriously positive response from our customers. We’ve had it on a few times in the last week, and people love it. Seriously tasty stuff. We are talking buttery shortbread, and a plum/red grape fruitiness that results in a sweet, tongue-tingling experience.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.clementcoffee.com/blogs/news/13082513-3-coe-filter-coffees-on-the-shelves</id>
    <published>2014-03-24T14:37:40+11:00</published>
    <updated>2014-03-24T14:38:30+11:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.clementcoffee.com/blogs/news/13082513-3-coe-filter-coffees-on-the-shelves"/>
    <title>3 CoE Filter coffees on the shelves</title>
    <author>
      <name>Jared Lawler</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><img src="http://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0403/3485/files/Screen_Shot_2014-03-24_at_2.37.50_pm.png?218" /></p>
<p>We have one incredible weekend lined up for you guys; we have not one, not two, but three brand new Cup of Excellence coffees in store for you to taste, roasted for filter, over this Saturday and Sunday.</p>
<p>If you’ve never heard of Cup Of Excellence, that’s ok, we can explain it to you. It’s essentially a competition and online auction, and also acts as an award given to prestigious coffees. They are evaluated, tasted and scored on their exemplary characteristics. The COE works off the SCAA (Specialty Coffee Association of America) approved cupping sheet that rate on a scale of 0-8 for aroma, defects, clean cup, sweet acidity, mouthfeel, flavour, aftertaste and balance in the palate. So if it has a COE award, it’s been chosen out of something like 500 coffees, been rated exceptionally, and been ranked and numbered. It’s fairly safe to say that anything COE is going to be exceptional.</p>
<p>Tasting info:</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Brazil Fransisco, COE #6</span></p>
<p>A ripe apricot sweetness, velvety mouth-feel, a long and elegant mouth-feel with a biscuity vanilla aftertaste.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Colombia Pozo Azul, COE #27</span></p>
<p>Pink Lady apple and fleshy stone-fruit flavours with tamarin and caramel.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Brazil Rainha, COE #17</span></p>
<p>Orange-chocolate jaffa, sweet hazelnuts and a great body.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.clementcoffee.com/blogs/news/13082501-kapsokisio</id>
    <published>2014-03-24T14:31:58+11:00</published>
    <updated>2014-03-24T14:37:17+11:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.clementcoffee.com/blogs/news/13082501-kapsokisio"/>
    <title>Kapsokisio</title>
    <author>
      <name>Jared Lawler</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>Hi everyone! So guess what? It’s new coffee time! Just when you thought you’d tried all of our coffees, feeling like you’d finally conquered Clement once and for all,  then we get in even more exciting exotic coffees for you to try. What assholes huh?! But don’t despair, rejoice! New coffee time is a time of awe and amazement, like watching the newest episode of Game of Thrones. Trust me, you will enjoy it.</p>
<p><img src="http://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0403/3485/files/Screen_Shot_2014-03-24_at_2.32.45_pm.png?214" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" /></p>
<p>So who is this mystery coffee?  Its name is Kapsokisio . Hailing from western Kenya on the border of Uganda, in the slopes of Mt. Elgon, the Kapsokisio Factory and Cooperative Society lies in a region with altitudes of 1600-1700 meters above sea level and has fertile soil rich in organic matter with a high water retention capacity. Essentially, it’s chock full of coffee plant super-food. </p>
<p><img src="http://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0403/3485/files/Screen_Shot_2014-03-24_at_2.32.39_pm.png?215" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" /></p>
<p>You too could be this happy, just drink some of this incredibly tasty coffee AND support small independent coffee farmers and their families! -http://timwendelboe.no/category/kenya/</p>
<p>Not as well established as central Kenya, western Kenya has great potential coffee production, but has been stunted by ongoing ethnic conflicts and violence. The community was hit hard during the post-election violence, where long held perceptions and historical rivalries were reignited, causing conflicts between tribes who had previously been co-existing peacefully. Only recently have farmers been able to return to their farms.</p>
<p><img src="http://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0403/3485/files/Screen_Shot_2014-03-24_at_2.32.31_pm.png?216" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" /></p>
<p>This guy knows where it’s at… parchment sorting, courtesy of<a href="http://nordicapproach.wordpress.com/">http://nordicapproach.wordpress.com/</a></p>
<p>Kenya has great altitudes, climate and soil, and all of these attributes have resulted in ideal growing conditions that produce an excellent quality and uniqueness in the cup. The Kapsokisio specifically has vibrant floral aromas, citrus and red-currant acidity. Very balanced and delicate, with a soft, juicy finish.</p>
<p><img src="http://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0403/3485/files/Screen_Shot_2014-03-24_at_2.32.17_pm.png?217" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" /></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.clementcoffee.com/blogs/news/13082449-bruseluas</id>
    <published>2014-03-24T14:30:50+11:00</published>
    <updated>2014-03-24T14:31:52+11:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.clementcoffee.com/blogs/news/13082449-bruseluas"/>
    <title>Bruseluas</title>
    <author>
      <name>Jared Lawler</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>A Colombian that’s got it all. The green bean brokers in the US, Coffee Shrub are sourcing some exciting Colombians and we’re loving this one.</p>
<p>Roasted for espresso and filter.</p>
<p> </p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img src="http://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0403/3485/files/Screen_Shot_2014-03-24_at_2.31.11_pm.png?213" /></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.clementcoffee.com/blogs/news/13082437-los-planes-el-salvador</id>
    <published>2014-03-24T14:28:51+11:00</published>
    <updated>2014-03-24T14:30:44+11:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.clementcoffee.com/blogs/news/13082437-los-planes-el-salvador"/>
    <title>Los Planes, El Salvador</title>
    <author>
      <name>Jared Lawler</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><span>This Former CoE winning pacamara has been vacuum packed since harvest 12 months ago so it is still full of its vibrant yet delicate citrus acidity.</span></p>
<p> </p>
<p><span><img src="http://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0403/3485/files/Screen_Shot_2014-03-24_at_2.29.20_pm.png?212" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" /></span></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.clementcoffee.com/blogs/news/13082401-rainha-brazil</id>
    <published>2014-03-24T14:26:15+11:00</published>
    <updated>2014-03-24T14:28:36+11:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.clementcoffee.com/blogs/news/13082401-rainha-brazil"/>
    <title>Rainha Brazil</title>
    <author>
      <name>Jared Lawler</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>Dirty? Borin<span style="line-height: 1.2;">g? Th</span><span style="line-height: 1.2;">ese two words have always been associated with Brazilian coffees.</span></p>
<p>Alas! This coffee is definately an exception to the ‘boring Brazil’. Times are changing for Brazilian coffees as farmers are planting interesting varietals and processing coffees with a level of care that is delivering coffees with character and interest.</p>
<p>There will be a number of different lots from this farm around Melbourne this year, including a Cup of Excellence winning coffee which we purchased (part of) in the Brazil CoE auction two days ago.</p>
<p>Don’t be fooled by the regularity of this coffee on different roasters shelves for it will taste fairly differe<span style="line-height: 1.2;">nt from roaster to roaster and lot to lot.</span></p>
<p> </p>
<p><img src="http://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0403/3485/files/Screen_Shot_2014-03-24_at_2.26.47_pm.png?211" style="line-height: 1.5; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" /></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
</feed>
